Guide to the Evarts Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- William Maxwell Evarts, 1830-1901; Series II; 14.75 linear feet (36 boxes)
  - Correspondence
    - Tweed, Helen Minerva (Evarts) (daughter), 1881, 1899, undated (Box 15, Folder 403)
    - Tweed, Helen (granddaughter), 1895 July 11 (Box 15, Folder 403)
    - Twiss, Travers, 1881, 1884 (Box 15, Folder 404)
    - Tyler, D. Gardiner, 1882, 1893 (Box 15, Folder 405)
    - Tyler, Julia G., 1881 January 25 (Box 15, Folder 405)
    - Tyler, Lachlan, 1879, 1881 (Box 15, Folder 406)
    - Tyner, James N., 1879 August 7 (Box 15, Folder 407)
    - Underwood, Levi, 1880 December 17 (Box 15, Folder 408)
    - United States Department of the Interior, United States Department of State (Box 15, Folder 408)
      See: box 12, folder 213
      See: box 15, folder 370
    - United States Naval Institute, Charles E. Monroe, 1881 February 16 (Box 15, Folder 409)
    - Vanderbilt, Rhoda, 1879 May 14 (Box 16, Folder 410)
    - Van Duzer, William A., 1878, 1880 (Box 16, Folder 410)
    - Van Nest, Margaret Taylor, 1880 May 29 (Box 16, Folder 410)
    - Van Santvoord, C., 1881 January 22 (Box 16, Folder 411)
    - Van Wart, Ames, 1883 December 6 (Box 16, Folder 411)
    - Van Winkle, Edgar S., 1869, 1881 (Box 16, Folder 412)
    - Van Zandt, Charles C., 1880 May 6 (Box 16, Folder 413)
    - Varnum, Joseph B., 1871 March 17 (Box 16, Folder 414)
    - Veeder, J. W., 1880 January 15 (Box 16, Folder 414)
    - Veteran Zouaves, J. Madison Drake, 1881 November 20 (Box 16, Folder 414)
    - Victory, John F., 1891 March (Box 16, Folder 415)
    - Vincent, Frank, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 415)
    - Voorhees, Daniel Wolsey, 1881 March 3 (Box 16, Folder 416)
    - Wait, John Turner (Box 16, Folder 416)
    - Waite, Amelia C., 1884 December 23 (Box 16, Folder 417)
    - Waite, Morrison Remick, 1879 December 1 (Box 16, Folder 417)
    - Wakeman, Abram, 1882 March 31 (Box 16, Folder 418)
    - Walden, George, 1881 March 16 (Box 16, Folder 418)
    - Ward., Julia E., 1881 January 20 (Box 16, Folder 419)
    - Ward, Rodney C., 1880 March 25 (Box 16, Folder 419)
    - Ward, Samuel, 1880-1881, undated (Box 16, Folder 420)
    - Wardner, Allen (father-in-law), 1845-1861 (Box 16, Folder 421)
      Letters To WME/From WME:7/14
    - Wardner, Henry, 1888 July 6 (Box 16, Folder 422)
    - Ware, L. W., 1880 May 15 (Box 16, Folder 422)
    - Warner, B. H., 1891 January 5 (Box 16, Folder 422)
    - Warren, James D., 1885 January 23 (Box 16, Folder 423)
    - Warren, Richard, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 423)
    - Warriner, W. A., 1885 January 25 (Box 16, Folder 424)
    - Washburn, E. A., 1880 February 26 (Box 16, Folder 425)
    - Washburn, Sarah E. (aunt), 1832 October 5 (Box 16, Folder 425)
    - Wass, Jerome B., 1879 October 29 (Box 16, Folder 425)
    - Watson, William, 1867 (Box 16, Folder 426)
      Letters To WME/From WME:1/2
    - Webb, Alexander Stewart, 1885 February 16 (Box 16, Folder 427)
    - Webster, E. D., 1879-1880 (Box 16, Folder 427)
    - Weed, Thurlow, 1864 January 11 (Box 16, Folder 428)
    - Welles, Charles Stuart, 1884 March 21 (Box 16, Folder 429)
    - Welsh, John, 1881 January 17 (Box 16, Folder 429)
    - Wescott, Charles Samuel (in re: typesetting machine), 1875-1876, undated (Box 16, Folder 430)
    - Westlake, John, 1864 February 4 (Box 16, Folder 431)
    - Weston, S. H., 1880 July 21 (Box 16, Folder 431)
    - Wetmore, Samuel, 1882 March 27 (Box 16, Folder 432)
    - Wetmore, William, 1885 February 2 (Box 16, Folder 432)
    - Wheeler, D. E., 1852 April 15 (Box 16, Folder 433)
    - Wheelock, John E., 1881 December 11 (Box 16, Folder 434)
    - Whipple, H. B., 1895 May 31 (Box 16, Folder 434)
    - White, Andrew D., 1881 (Box 16, Folder 435)
    - Whitehouse, William Fitzhugh, 1870 December 1 (Box 16, Folder 436)
    - Wiggin, Benjamin, 1859 January 11 (Box 16, Folder 437)
    - Williker, Charles M., 1884 May 12 (Box 16, Folder 437)
    - Wilson, Benjamin W., 1879 November 25 (Box 16, Folder 438)
    - Wilson, Edward, Jr., 1881 (Box 16, Folder 438)
    - Wilson, James Grant, 1891 May 2 (Box 16, Folder 438)
    - Wilson, Joseph S. (in re: Tajauta Ranch case), 1869, 1870 (Box 16, Folder 439)
    - Wilson, S. F., 1886 January 5 (Box 16, Folder 439)
    - Windsor Saving Bank (Windsor, Vermont), 1849, 1850 (Box 16, Folder 440)
    - Windsor, Vermont, S. N. Stone for town committee, 1894 May 23 (Box 16, Folder 441)
    - Wingard, S. C., 1885 December 31 (Box 16, Folder 442)
    - Winthrop, Robert Charles, 1880-1889 (Box 16, Folder 443)
    - Wise, Morris S., 1885 (Box 16, Folder 444)
    - Wood, A. B., 1885 (Box 16, Folder 445)
    - Wood, James, 1880 January 14 (Box 16, Folder 446)
    - William Wood and Company, 1886 April 21 (Box 16, Folder 446)
    - Woodford, Stewart L., 1879, 1882 (Box 16, Folder 446)
    - Worthington, G. W., 1885 March 26 (Box 16, Folder 447)
    - Wortman, Denis, 1896 December 2 (Box 16, Folder 447)
    - Wright, Ebenezer, 1879 January 10 (Box 16, Folder 447)
    - Yale Alumni Association, 1870-1894 (Box 16, Folder 448)
    - Yarnall, Thomas C., 1879 October 29 (Box 16, Folder 449)
    - Yerkes, Stephen, 1880, 1894 (Box 16, Folder 450)
    - Young, John Russell, 1880 May 21 (Box 16, Folder 451)
    - Unidentified: unsigned letter to William Maxwell Evarts, 1864 February 22 (Box 16, Folder 452)
    - Unidentified, 1868, 1891-1899, undated (Box 16, Folder 453)
    - Invitations to William Maxwell Evarts and Mrs. Evarts, 1864-1901 (Box 16, Folder 453)
      See: box 37
    - Letters to William Maxwell Evarts re: speaking engagements, 1880-1891 (Box 16, Folder 454)
    - Letter from prominent New Yorkers to William Maxwell Evarts on his return from Washington, D. C., and draft of his reply, 1881 March (Box 16, Folder 455)
    - List of individuals who wrote to William Maxwell Evarts in re: appointment of a collector, United States Revenue Service, 1st District, New York, 1879-1880 (Box 16, Folder 456)
    - Letter from prominent New Yorkers to William Maxwell Evarts on his return from Washington, D. C., and draft of his reply, 1881 March (Box 16, Folder 455)
    - List of individuals who wrote to William Maxwell Evarts in re: appointment of a collector, United States Revenue Service, 1st District, New York, 1879-1880 (Box 16, Folder 456)
    - Letters of congratulations: election to the United States Senate
      - A - B, 1885 January-March (Box 17, Folder 457)
      - C - F, 1885 January March (Box 17, Folder 458)
      - G - L, 1885 January March (Box 17, Folder 459)
      - M - Q, 1885 January March (Box 17, Folder 460)
      - R - S, 1885 January-March (Box 17, Folder 461)
      - T - Z, 1885 January-March (Box 17, Folder 462)
      - telegrams, A - Z, 1885 January (Box 17, Folder 463)
    - Letters of congratulations: Golden Wedding Anniversary
      - A - C, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 464)
      - D - H, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 465)
      - I - Z, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 466)
      - telegrams, A - Z, 1893 (Box 17, Folder 467)
    - Correspondence of others
      - general, 1851, 1863, 1885, 1886 (Box 17, Folder 468)
      - ALS from Joseph Henry Adams to George Bartlett Prescott, 1884 June 21 (Box 17, Folder 469)
      - letter acknowledging receipt of portrait of William Maxwell Evarts sent by Travelers' Insurance Company, 1884 (Box 17, Folder 470)
      - TLS from the United States Department of State to Katharine Tweed Blaine, enclosing copies of correspondence relating to William Maxwell Evarts' mission to London in 1863, 1921 June 4 (Box 17, Folder 471)
  - Legal Papers
    - Admiralty Prize Court and Court of Appeal, report of cases, 1854-1855 (Box 18, Folder 472)
    - Admiralty Prize Court and Court of Appeal, report of cases (copy 2), 1854-1855 (Box 18, Folder 473)
    - Alabama claims (Geneva Arbitration Tribunal), in re (Box 18, Folder 474)
    - Antoni v. Greenhow (Box 18, Folder 475)
    - Appleby et al. v. Firemen's Fund Insurance Company (Box 18, Folder 476)
    - Aspinwall v. Ramsay et al. (Box 18, Folder 477)
    - Aspinwall v. Torrance et al. (Box 18, Folder 477)
    - Baker v. Drake (Box 19, Folder 478)
    - Bank tax cases (Box 19, Folder 479-481)
    - Bank tax cases (Box 19, Folder 482)
    - Bank tax cases (Box 19, Folder 482)
      See also: box 35, folder 660
    - Barnard v. Monnot (Box 19, Folder 483)
    - Barrett et al. v. Coster et al. (Box 19, Folder 484-485)
    - Barstow v. New York Mail Steamship Company (Box 19, Folder 486)
    - Bartlett v. Torrance (Box 19, Folder 486)
      See: box 18, folder 477
    - Beekman v. New York et al. (Box 20, Folder 487)
    - Benkard et al. v. Schell (Box 20, Folder 488)
    - Best et al. v. New York Life Insurance Company (Box 20, Folder 489)
    - Bowne v. Duryea, Leveridge, et al. (Box 20, Folder 490)
    - Boyd v. Tyler (Box 20, Folder 491)
    - Boylan v. United States (Box 20, Folder 492)
    - Brown et al. v. Comstock et al. (Box 20, Folder 493)
    - Brown et al. v. Kohnstamm et al. (Box 20, Folder 493)
    - Brown et al. v. Comstock et al. (Box 20, Folder 494)
    - Brown et al. v. Kohnstamm et al. (Box 20, Folder 494)
    - Burden v. Corning et al. (Box 20, Folder 495-497)
    - Burdette v. Estey (organ case) (Box 20, Folder 498)
    - Butler v. Tappen, trustee, under the marriage settlement of Elijah Ward and E. E. Ward, et al. (Box 21, Folder 499)
    - Butt v. Cameron (Box 21, Folder 500)
    - Carpenter v. Jaudon (Box 21, Folder 501)
    - Casey, Cudmore, and Company v. Barney (Box 21, Folder 502)
    - Cheever and Hart et al. v. R. and B. Railroad Company et al. (Box 21, Folder 503)
    - Christie and Bill v. De Friest (Box 21, Folder 503)
      See: box 34, folder 646
    - Churchill et al. v. City of Utica (Box 21, Folder 503)
      See: box 19, folders 479-481
    - Clark et al. v. United States (Box 21, Folder 504)
    - Code of Civil Procedure, by David Dudley Field, in re (Box 21, Folder 505)
    - Colgate v. Russell (Box 21, Folder 506)
    - [Conner?] v. City of New York (Box 21, Folder 507)
    - Cowdrey v. Pacific Railroad Company et al. (Box 21, Folder 508)
    - Crapo et al. v. Kelly (Box 21, Folder 509)
    - Kelly V. Crapo et al. (Box 21, Folder 509)
    - Dawson, Thomas M., in re: claims presented to Congress(1877) (Box 21, Folder 510)
    - De Haro v. United States (Box 21, Folder 511)
    - Delafield v. Parish et al. (Parish Will case) (Box 21, Folder 512-513)
    - Delafield v. Parish et al. (Parish Will case) (Box 22, Folder 514-517)
    - Dennistoun and Company v. Draper (Box 23, Folder 518)
    - Dodge v. Pond et al. (Phelps Will case) (Box 23, Folder 519)
    - Draper v. The Commercial Insurance Company (Box 23, Folder 520)
    - Draper v. The Columbia Insurance Company (Box 23, Folder 520)
    - Drexel et al. v. Gill et al. (Box 23, Folder 521)
    - D'Wolf, trustee, v. D'Wolf et al. (Box 23, Folder 522-523)
    - Electoral Commission of 1877, (untitled brief) (Box 23, Folder 524)
    - Farmers' Loan and Trust Company v. McHenry (Box 23, Folder 525)
    - Farrington v. Saunders (cotton tax case) (Box 23, Folder 526)
    - Field, David Dudley (Box 23, Folder 526)
      See: box 21, folder 505
    - Fitzpatrick v. Cotton, 276 bales ( George W. Hynson case) (Box 24, Folder 527)
    - Floyd Brothers and Company v. S. S. C. Company (Box 24, Folder 528)
    - Gardiner et al. v. Tyler et al. (Box 24, Folder 529-531)
    - German Savings Bank v. Archbold (Box 24, Folder 532)
    - Gillender et al. v. Pearl (Box 24, Folder 533)
    - Goodyear v. Phoenix Rubber Company (Box 24, Folder 534)
    - Goodyear Metallic Rubber Shoe Company v. Pritchard (Box 24, Folder 535)
    - Great T[ _____ Mining, Manufacturing, and Trust Company?] v. Phillips and St. John (Box 24, Folder 536)
    - Great Western Insurance Company v. Fogarty (Box 24, Folder 537)
    - Greeff et al. v. Draper (Box 24, Folder 538)
    - Hadden et al. v. Merritt (Box 24, Folder 539)
    - Hartford and New Haven Railroad Company v. New York and New Haven Railroad Company (Box 24, Folder 540)
    - Harwood et al. v. Mitchell et al. (Box 24, Folder 541)
    - Haskins, a bankrupt, in re (Box 25, Folder 542)
    - Heale v. Hamilton (Box 25, Folder 543)
    - Heilman v. Roberts (Box 25, Folder 544)
    - Heney, Christopher, in re: estate of (Box 25, Folder 545)
    - Home Insurance Company v. Morse and Paige (Box 25, Folder 546)
    - Hopkins v. Grinnell (Box 25, Folder 547)
    - Howland and Aspinwall, in re (San Juan estate) (Box 25, Folder 548)
    - Hoyt, Jesse, deceased, in re: last will and testament of (Box 25, Folder 549)
    - Hoyt, Jesse (Box 25, Folder 549)
      See also: box 33, folder 637
    - Kelly v. Crapo et al. (Box 25, Folder 549)
      See: box 21, folder 509
    - Letson v. Rutler (Box 25, Folder 550)
    - Leupp, Charles M., in re: estate of (Box 25, Folder 551)
    - Liverpool and London Fire and Life Insurance Company, in re (Box 25, Folder 552)
    - Lord, executor, v. Mills et al. (Box 26, Folder 553)
    - Louisiana Mutual Insurance Company v. Tweed (Box 26, Folder 554)
    - Lovett v. Kingsland et al. (Lovett Will case) (Box 26, Folder 555-556)
    - Manice v. Gould (Box 26, Folder 557)
    - Matthews v. McStea (Box 26, Folder 558)
    - Merchants Bank v. State Bank (Box 26, Folder 559)
    - Merritt v. Thompson (Box 26, Folder 560)
    - Merritt v. Welsh et al. (sugar case) (Box 26, Folder 561)
    - Mitchell v. Tilghman (Box 27, Folder 562)
    - Tilghman v. Mitchell (Box 27, Folder 562)
    - Murphy v. Lockwood (Box 27, Folder 563)
    - Murphy v. Murphy (Box 27, Folder 564)
    - New Mexico v. Beall et al. (Box 27, Folder 565)
    - New York v. Board of Police of the Metropolitan Police District (Box 27, Folder 566-569)
    - New York v. Bowen et al. (Box 27, Folder 570)
    - New York v. Haws and the City of New York (Box 28, Folder 571)
    - New York v. Lowber and the City of New York (Box 28, Folder 572)
    - New York v. Moring (Box 28, Folder 573)
    - New York v. Murray et al. (Box 28, Folder 574)
    - New York ex rel. Bank of the Commonwealth v. City of New York (Box 28, Folder 574)
    - New York ex rel. Murphy v. Kelly (Brooklyn Bridge case) (Box 28, Folder 575-576)
    - New York ex rel. Taylor and Brennan v. City of New York(West Washington Market case) (Box 28, Folder 577)
    - New York ex rel. Taylor et al. v. Brennan (Fort Gansevoort case) (Box 28, Folder 578)
    - New York Cable Railway Company, in re: the petition of (Box 29, Folder 579)
    - New York Cable Railway Company v. Second Avenue Railway Company (Box 29, Folder 580-581)
    - New York Mail Steamship Company v. Atlantic Mail Steamship Company (Box 29, Folder 582)
    - New York Protestant Episcopal Public School v. Hope (Box 29, Folder 583)
    - Northern Railroad Company et al. v. Ogdensburgh and Champlain Railroad Company et al. (Box 29, Folder 584)
    - Norton, Slaughter, and Company v. various insurance companies (submitted to arbitration by William Maxwell Evarts, George T. Hope, and Robert M. Hening) (Box 29, Folder 585)
    - Nuestra Senora de Regla, in re (Box 29, Folder 586)
    - Ohio Southern Railroad Company, in re (Box 29, Folder 587)
    - Oregon and California Railroad Company, in re (Box 29, Folder 588)
    - Osborne et al. v. McCormick (Box 29, Folder 589)
    - Paddock v. Church of the Puritans (Box 29, Folder 590)
    - Patterson v. Baker (Box 29, Folder 591)
    - Perkins, Benjamin W., in re: claims against the Russian government (Box 30, Folder 592)
    - Perry v. Draper (Box 30, Folder 593)
    - Phenix Bank v. Risley (Box 30, Folder 594)
    - Pleasants v. Greenhow (Box 30, Folder 595)
    - Poindexter v. Greenhow (Box 30, Folder 596)
    - Post et al. v. Weil (Box 30, Folder 597)
    - Post et al. v. Bernheimer (Box 30, Folder 597)
    - Potter v. Dixon (Box 30, Folder 598)
    - Providence and Stonington Steamship Company v. Phenix Insurance Company et al. (Box 30, Folder 599)
    - Pullman Palace Car Company v. Wagner (Box 30, Folder 600)
    - Pumpelly, Harmon, in re: will of (Box 30, Folder 601)
    - Rapid Transit Act (Box 30, Folder 601)
      See: box 29, folder 579
    - Rebecca, in re the (Box 30, Folder 602)
    - Ridley v. Sherbrooke (Box 30, Folder 603)
    - Rose v. Rose et al. (Rose will case) (Box 30, Folder 604)
    - Rose v. Spofford et al. (Box 30, Folder 605)
    - Rumford Chemical Works, in re (Box 30, Folder 605)
      See: box 15, folder 361
    - Rutland Marble Company v. Ripley (Box 30, Folder 606)
    - Ripley v. Rutland Marble Company (Box 30, Folder 606)
    - Sedgwick v. Sparkman et al. (Box 30, Folder 607)
    - Seward, Olive Risley, in re: Virginia farm of (Box 30, Folder 608)
    - Slossen v. Ogden et al. (in re: marriage settlement of Mrs. C. E. Lawrence) (Box 31, Folder 609)
    - Smith, James R., in re: estate of (Box 31, Folder 610)
    - Smith v. Draper (Box 31, Folder 611)
    - Southern Pacific Railroad Companies of Arizona and New Mexico, in re (Texas Pacific Railroad land grant) (Box 31, Folder 612)
    - Springbok, in re the (Box 31, Folder 613)
    - Stanley et al. v. Colt (Box 31, Folder 614-615)
    - Steam Stone Cutter Company v. Sears (Box 31, Folder 616)
    - Stokes, James, deceased, in re: the will of (Box 31, Folder 617)
    - Sumner v. New York Mail Steamship Company (Box 31, Folder 618)
    - Thompson v. Perrine (Box 31, Folder 619)
    - Tucker v. Noyes (Box 31, Folder 620)
    - Uhler v. Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box 32, Folder 621)
    - Union Pacific Railroad Company, in re (Box 32, Folder 622)
    - United States v. Anderson, executor of the last will and testament of Thaddeus Phelps deceased (Box 32, Folder 623)
    - United States v. Baker et al. (Box 32, Folder 624)
    - United States v. Cutting (Box 32, Folder 625)
    - United States v. Fisk et al. (Box 32, Folder 625)
    - United States v. Jefferson Davis (Box 32, Folder 626-631)
    - United States v. Jefferson Davis (Box 32, Folder 632-635)
    - United States v. Henderson (Box 33, Folder 636)
    - United States v. Hoyt (Box 33, Folder 637)
    - [United States v. Kupfer et al.?], alleged violation of internal revenue laws, tax on distilled spirits (Box 33, Folder 638)
    - United States v. Lee (Box 33, Folder 639)
    - United States v. 113 hogsheads, etc. containing sugar ( Bell Barnard case) (Box 33, Folder 640)
    - United States v. Ruggles (Box 33, Folder 641)
    - United States v. 600 cases of champagne (Box 33, Folder 642)
    - United States v. E. and J. Willets and Company (Box 33, Folder 643)
    - Van Blarcom v. Broadway Bank (Box 34, Folder 644)
    - Van Dyck v. Metropolitan Bank and the Shoe and Leather Bank (Box 34, Folder 645)
    - Van Rensselaer v. Ball (Box 34, Folder 646)
    - Van Rensselaer v. Chadwick (Box 34, Folder 646)
    - Van Rensselaer v. Hayes (Box 34, Folder 646)
    - Walker v. Gilbert et al. (Box 34, Folder 647)
    - Wallach v. Raynor (Box 34, Folder 648)
    - Ward v. Maryland (Box 34, Folder 649)
    - Ward and Butler, trustees, v. Meacham et al. (Box 34, Folder 650)
    - Warren, Richard, assignee for Caleb Barstow and creditors, v. St. Nicholas National Bank and W. R. Fosdick (Box 34, Folder 651)
    - Wescott, Charles Samuel, in re (Box 34, Folder 652)
    - Williams v. Western Union Telegraph Company (Box 34, Folder 653)
    - Winnebago and O. K. Mining Company, in re (Box 34, Folder 654)
    - Woerishoffer v. North River Construction Company (Box 34, Folder 655-656)
    - [Woodrow?) v. Murdock (Box 34, Folder 657)
    - Unidentified cases: briefs, notes, memoranda (Box 35, Folder 658)
    - Unidentified cases: briefs, notes, memoranda (Box 35, Folder 659)
    - Deeds, wills, legal papers of clients of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 35, Folder 659)
      See also: box 49A
    - Deeds, mortgages, contracts of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 35, Folder 659)
      See: box 49A
    - Opinions
      - William Maxwell Evarts, 1865-1866, 1867-1876, 1882-1884 (Box 35, Folder 660-662)
      - Charles O'Conor, 1861 February 4, 1873 June 21, undated (Box 35, Folder 663)
      - Edward Jordan, 1865 February 8 (Box 35, Folder 663)
      - H. H. Emmons, 1871 May (Box 35, Folder 663)
      - Charles C. Beaman, 1880 March (Box 35, Folder 663)
      - J. Daniels, 1884 (Box 35, Folder 663)
  - Congressional Papers
    - Bills and reports, 49th Congress, 1st session (Box 35, Folder 664)
    - Bills and reports, 49th Congress, 2nd session (Box 35, Folder 665)
    - Bills and reports, 50th Congress (Box 35, Folder 666)
    - Bills and reports, 51st Congress, 1st and 2nd sessions (Box 35, Folder 667)
    - In re: petition of Schuyler Hamilton to the United States Congress, 1886-1887 (Box 35, Folder 668)
    - In re: claims of John A. Machado against the Spanish government in Cuba, Circa 1887 (Box 35, Folder 669)
    - Remarks on the brig General Armstrong, and its captain, Samuel Chester Reid (author unknown), undated (Box 35, Folder 670)
    - Docket, applicants for positions in government service, Volume I, 1889 January-December (Box 36, Folder 671)
    - Docket, applicants for positions in government service, Volume II, 1889 December-1891 November (Box 36, Folder 672)
  - Memorabilia
    - Invitations, calling cards, and notices (Box 37)
      - Invitations, London, 1864 (Box 37, Folder 673-674)
      - Calling cards, London, 1864 (Box 37, Folder 675)
      - Visiting book of Mrs. William M. Evarts, New York, Washington, D. C., 1866-1869 (Box 37, Folder 676)
      - Invitations and notices, 1878-1879 (Box 37, Folder 677)
      - Presidential invitations (Hayes), 1879-1881 (Box 37, Folder 678)
      - Wedding invitations, 1879-1885, n.y. (Box 37, Folder 679)
      - Invitations and notices, 1880-1901, undated (Box 37, Folder 680-682)
      - Invitations and notices, Evarts family, undated (Box 37, Folder 683)
      - Calling cards, undated (Box 37, Folder 684)
    - Dinners and commemorative events (Box 38)
      - Programs, commemorative events, 1865-1885 (Box 38, Folder 685)
      - Complimentary dinner: William Maxwell Evarts, 1868 (Box 38, Folder 686)
      - Complimentary dinners: Hon. J. G. Blaine, 1878 December 13 (Box 38, Folder 687)
      - Goldwin Smith, 1879 February 20 (Box 38, Folder 687)
      - Diplomatic dinners, 1879-1880 January (Box 38, Folder 688-689)
      - Complimentary dinners: J. J. Astor, 1880 February 6 (Box 38, Folder 690)
      - Mme. de Hegermann, 1880 March 18 (Box 38, Folder 690)
      - Cyrus W. Field, 1880 October 26 (Box 38, Folder 690)
      - Diplomatic dinner (Box 38, Folder 691-692)
      - Dinners (Box 38, Folder 693)
      - Dinner to General Porfirio Diaz by General U. S. Grant, 1883 April (Box 38, Folder 694)
      - Dinner to John C. Spooner, 1891 March (Box 38, Folder 694)
      - Golden Wedding Anniversary of William Maxwell Evarts and Helen M. W. Evarts, 1893 August 30 (Box 38, Folder 695)
    - Speeches and notes, William Maxwell Evarts (Box 39, Folder 695)
      - Oration delivered before the Linonian Society of Yale College, 1853 (Box 39, Folder 696)
      - Republican Union Festival in commemoration of the birth of George Washington, 1862 February 22 (Box 39, Folder 697)
      - Eulogy on Chief-Justice Chase, 1874 June 24 (Box 39, Folder 698)
      - International Monetary Conference, Paris, 1881 May 19 (Box 39, Folder 699)
      - Address in memory of Thomas A. Hendricks in the United States Senate, 1886 January 26 (Box 39, Folder 700)
      - Remarks on the bust of Garibaldi, United States Senate, 1888 August 23 (Box 39, Folder 700)
      - "Memorandum notes of my visit Europe, 1863. No. 1." (William Maxwell Evarts), 1863 April 18-30 (Box 39, Folder 701)
      - Notes, 1893, 1895, undated (Box 39, Folder 702)
    - Yale memorabilia, memorial tributes, and reminiscences
      - School report and lessons, 1830-1833, undated (Box 39, Folder 703)
      - Record of the Class of 1837, Yale College, 1873 (Box 39, Folder 704)
      - Reunion schedules, 1882 (Box 39, Folder 704)